Aman Bhuiyan

E: aub204@yahoo.com

M: 07954 2259 44

London, United Kingdom

 With 7 years of IT Systems / software development, maintenance, and support experience, I am a motivated software developer having great enthusiasm in Python cloud / Big Data speciality. My background is from Information Technology. I have BSc (CSE) & MSc degree in IT. I am problem solver with can do attitude. I can take responsibilities and enjoy learning new things.

Technical skills:

AWS: AWS Lambda, AWS cloud platform, AWS services, EC2,

S3, RDS, Dynamodb, Cloudformation, Cloudwatch, VPC, ELB, EFS, Route53, Cloudfront, CI/CD Pipeline,

Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible.

Azure: Microsoft Azure (Compute, Storage, Networking),

Azure Virtual machines, containers, Storage account,

Azure function, ARM, Virtual Network, CI/CD

Programming Languages: Python, C#, Scala

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jquery

Database / BI: Relational database, SQL, and non relational database

DynamoDB

Operating system: Linux

Development tools: Visual studio 2008, 2010, 2013, Visual web developer

Net beans,

S/W development methodologies: Agile, TDD, SCRUM

S/W testing: Unit testing, Nunit, System testing

Hands-on AWS experience

- Creating AWS Labmda function /services and triggering these through various AWS services
- Programming in python
- Demonstrable knowledge of AWS CloudFormation, EC2, S3, and similar technologies
- Demonstrable knowledge of AWS security layers like VPCs/NACLs, Security Groups, IAM roles, etc
- Monitoring AWS Environment
- Cost management Reducing AWS maintenance Cost
- Solid understanding of code pipelines & release chains
- Linux server administration
- Excellent communication skills at all levels including a wide range of stakeholders within the business
- Highly skilled in the improvement of processes & systems
- Problem solves within tight deadlines
- pro-active and take initiative and encourage teams to do the same
- Knowledge and ability to use relevant internal systems
- AWS Associate Certification getting ready for AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate level

Professional Experience:

1. Senior Developer

Lewisham Council, London, May 2019 - continue

Responsibilities:

- Lead in Application and Data Migration to cloud
- Creating and managing Data Migration environment
- Automate data migration
- Client facing consultancy with hands-on technical delivery

2. Systems Developer / Consultant

Dec 2017- February 2019

Shoosmiths LLP

Northampton

Responsibilities:

Systems Development and Administration

- Responsible for development and new enhancement of organisation's Legal product
- Design, develop and maintain key software components using SharePoint,
 C#, Microsoft SQL Server, K2, and Microsoft SharePoint Server in accordance with organisation's Software and Security Development Lifecycles.
- Test developed software and resolve any issues, ensuring Shoosmiths' systems operate in a reliable manner.
- Release of software version to UAT and production.
- Ensure appropriate documentation is created and maintained for all system developments.
- Work with Project Managers, providing accurate development estimates as requested.
- Ensure systems change management is carried out in accordance with agreed standards and procedures.

3. SharePoint Developer

July 2016 - Dec 2017

Ince & Co LLP

London

Responsibilities:

- Analysing systems, finding program needs, consulting with users, getting clients requirements, documenting technical specifications.
- Creating Web parts, Application pages, event relievers using SharePoint, ASP.Net, C#, and SQL Servers.
- Remodelling and re-structuring old classic asp application to brand new application using new technologies
 - Managing systems in **development**, **test and production** environment
- Deploy developed and tested solutions from dev to test or production environment
- Debugging, testing, modifying and correcting errors of existing system and updating whenever necessary.

- backed development using C#, Asp.net, Sql Server.
- Creating nice interactive user interface using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery.
- managing codes in source control systems in TFS or Tortious SVN in accordance with organisations standards / procedures.
- Writing Technical, documentation, user documentation and business process for IT Systems.

4. Systems Developer

January - June, 2016

Building Research Establishment, London

Responsibilities:

- I was involved on setting up and configuring SharePoint environment. I have created three tiers SharePoint farm on windows Hyper V.
- I have also created SharePoint farm on Windows Azure and maintained it.
- Created complex SSRS report from SharePoint, SQL Server, Data warehouse, data mart.
- Maintained and supported SharePoint application, visual studio custom solution.

5. Systems Developer

April 2015 - Aug-2015

Capita IT Enterprise Services & NHS- Central London Community Health Care NHS Trust

London

Responsibilities:

- I was involved in taking leadership of developing **SharePoint/.Net** systems, and managed business process for **SharePoint e-forms** for different department of client.
- I was involved of SharePoint **intranet Migration**. I have analyzed the option and selected the best option for developing a new intranet.

- Administering SharePoint farm / environment, developing and maintaining SharePoint workflows, list, libraries, forms, features / solutions.
- Taking leadership to reduce the number of SharePoint / BI related service desk call assigned to development team related with systems/software
- Created SharePoint BI reports, SSRS projects, SSIS packages and ETL / data warehouse. I had researched and got skills on K2 workflow, smart object, Smartforms, view etc.

6. Systems Developer April 2013 to April 2015

The Royal Liverpool & Broadgreen University Hospital NHS Trust

Responsibilities:

- Take Lead responsibility in any systems issue across the organisation
- Branding SharePoint site, creating web parts, application pages, event receivers, farm and sandbox solutions, dealing with large data
- Using front end technologies html, css, javascript, jquery, bootstrap

7. Web developer / Freelancer

June, 2011- April 2013

- Building website and web application from scratch
- Creating Sharepoint solutions
- Making professional website using CMS, Wordpress, Joomla
- Creating database, ssis solutions using Microsoft sql server
- Experience of glikview, Tableau, Cognos BI
- Skills of Sharepoint EDMS, Sharepoint ECM, Record management
- Developing, Managing, maintaining of websites, using cms, (joomla, wordpress,) and in asp.net
- Using C# , SQL server, ASP.net , mentoring C#, SQL Server,
- Using SQL server reporting services
- Using software development lifecycle and documentation skills

Training Course attended:

Course title	Training provider	Duration	Year
			completed
AWS Certified Solution	Udemy – A cloud	20 hours	2018
Architect- Associate	guru		
Windows Azure Mobile Services	Microsoft	1 day	2013
(A Lap around)			
Kubernetes certification course	Udemy	5.5 hours	2018
with practical tests			

Education:

1. MSc in Information Technology

University of East London London, UK, Nov, 2009- March, 2011. **3 distinctions, 4 credits out of 8 courses**

2. BSC: Computer Science and Engineering

Jahangiragar University
Dhaka, Bangladesh, 2000-2005, 1st Class

References: Available on request.